Finding Aid for the Al Pearce Papers PASC.0320
UCLA Library Special Collections
Al Pearce papers
1938-1946
UCLA Library Special Collections
Pearce, Al
PASC.0320
14.0 Linear Feet (8 boxes and 7 album boxes)
Comedian Al Pearce became an established name in radio and was best known for playing Elmer Blurt, a self-conscious door-to-door salesman. The collection consists of script files, sound recordings, and photographs related to Pearce's radio career as well as a small amount of memorabilia.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Audio materials in this collection are restricted and require advance notice for use.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9962898293606533
Biography
Albert Walter Pearce was born July 25, 1898 in San Jose, CA. Pearce worked as a door-to-door insurance salesman for a time, but eventually went into the real estate business in San Francisco, CA with his brother Cal Pearce. In the late 1920s, Pearce got a position as a singer at a local radio station, KFRC. At KFRC, he was introduced to Jack Hasty who asked Pearce to play the lead role in a skit he had written, as Elmer Blurp (later changed to Elmer Blurt). Elmer Blurp was a character that Pearce easily identified with: a self-conscious salesman. In 1929, KFRC featured Pearce in T he Happy-Go-Lucky Hour, which ran for four years. Pearce was joined on air by his brother Cal Pearce, Abe Bloom, Charles Carter, Jean Clarimoux, Edna Fischer, Tommy Harris, Norman Nielsen, Monroe Upton, Hazel Warner, and Cecil Wright.
The radio program changed names and stations in 1933, becoming Al Pearce and His Gang and broadcasted on the National Broadcasting Company (NBC) Blue Network. The comedy-variety program was broadcasted from 1933 through 1946 on Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) and NBC. The show had many prominent sponsors including: Pepsodent, Ford Motors, Grape Nuts, Dole Pineapple, and Camel Cigarettes. During the show's tenure, Pearce's gang included Arlene Harris, Bill Comstock, Jennison Parker, Bill Wright, Monroe Upton, Artie Auerbach, Kitty O'Neil, and Harry Stewart. Al Pearce and His Gang is most memorable for the skits of Elmer Blurt selling insurance door-to-door with his distinct knock followed by the famous tagline, "Nobody home, I hope-I hope-I hope." In 1943 the Elmer skit was turned into a feature length film titled Here Comes Elmer, starring Pearce as Elmer Blurt.
Pearce had another radio show, Fun Valley, which was broadcasted for one season on the American Broadcasting Company (ABC) Blue Network from 1943 through 1944. The program was a comedic variety show that included short skits and musical numbers. Pearce was joined on the show by regulars Arlene Harris, Wendell Niles, and Ivan Ditmars.
In addition to his radio projects, Pearce made several film and television appearances including the motion pictures Here Comes Elmer (1943), Hitchhike to Happiness (1945), One Exciting Week (1946), and The Main Street Kid (1948). His public career seemed to disappear during the 1950s. Pearce died on June 2, 1961 in Newport Beach, California due to heart disease (confirmed by a copy of his Certificate of Death found in the collection).
Scope and Content
Collection consists of materials related to the career of radio and television comedian Al Pearce. Includes script files, transcription disks, photographs that appear mostly related to radio programs in which Pearce was involved; and a small amount of memorabilia. The script files include drafts of completed and revised scripts and script pages for multiple radio shows, among them The Al Pearce Show, Al Pearce and His Gang, The Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes, Fun Valley, Here Comes Elmer, The Life of Elmer Blurt, and Backstage in Broadcasting. The transcription disks include twelve and sixteen inch platters of selected Pearce radio shows; the bulk of the recordings are of The Al Pearce Show and Here Comes Elmer. The photographs are headshots of Pearce and promotional shots related to Pearce's career. Additionally, there is a small amount of personal memorabilia and an Al Pearce and His Happy Prune Pickers recipe booklet.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Memorabilia, 1930s-1960s.
Photographs, 1930s-1940s.
Scripts, 1938-1946.
Transcription disks, 1939-1945.
Comedians -- United States -- Archives.; Sound recordings.; Radio scripts; Radio actors and actresses -- California -- Archives.; Pearce, Al -- Archives
- Memorabilia
  - Al Pearce and His Happy Prune Pickers - recipe booklet, no dates (Box 1)
  - News From ABC, 1946 Jan 16 (Box 6)
    General note
    Promo-like newsletter or script that mentions the Al Pearce Show.
  - Personal memorabilia, no dates (Box 1)
    Pearce's business card, personal stationery, Social Security card, last will and testament, death certificate, and marriage certificate.
- Photographs
  - Head shots of Al Pearce, no dates (Box 1)
  - Photographs with Pearce and Jackie Cooper, William Powell, and [Gene Autry?], no dates (Box 1)
  - Promotional photographs for Pearce's program(s), no dates (Box 1)
    Appears to be for promotional purposes.
  - Promotional photographs with Scarab car and Ford truck., no dates (Box 1)
  - Unidentified people and events. May be related to Pearce's career, no dates (Box 1)
- Script Material
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1938 Oct 10 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1938 Oct 17 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1938 Oct 24 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Nov 1 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Nov 29 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Nov 8 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Oct 18 (Box 1)
    (2 copies)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Oct 25 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Dec 13 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Dec 20 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1939 Dec 6 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Apr 3 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Feb 14 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Feb 28 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Feb 7 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Jan 10 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Jan 17 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Jan 24 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Jan 3 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Jan 31 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Mar 27 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1940 Mar 6 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 1 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 2 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 3 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 4 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 5 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 8 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Feb 1 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Feb 4 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jan 23 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jan 30 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jan 31 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 13 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 14 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 15 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 18 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 19 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 20 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 21 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 22 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 26 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Mar 27 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 10 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 11 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 12 (Box 7)
    (3 copies)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 15 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 16 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 17 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 18 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 19 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 22 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 23 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 24 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 25 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 26 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 29 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 30 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Apr 9 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 13 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 14 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 17 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 18 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 19 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 21 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 24 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 25 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 3 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 4 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 5 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun? 20 (Box 7)
    Appears to be for June 20, 1946.
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 1 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 2 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 22 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 23 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 24 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 27 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 28 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 29 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 3 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 30 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 31 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 6 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 7 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 May 8 (Box 7)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 1 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 14 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 15 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 16 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 19 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 20 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 21 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 22 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 23 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 27 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 28 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Aug 29 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 1 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 10 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 11 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 12 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 2 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 29 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 3 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 30 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 31 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 4 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 5 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 8 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jul 9 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 26 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 27 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Jun 28 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce and His Gang script, 1946 Sep 11 (Box 8)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jul 19 (Box 2)
    First draft and final draft.
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jul 5 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jun 14 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jun 21 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jun 28 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jun 28 (Box 2)
    First draft, second draft and final draft.
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jun 7 (Box 2)
    First draft (2 copies), second draft, and final draft.
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 May 10 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 May 17 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 May 24 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 May 3 (Box 2)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Aug 16 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Aug 2 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Aug 23 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Aug 9 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Jul 26 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Sep 20 (Box 3)
    First draft and final (2 copies) draft.
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1940 Sep 27 (Box 3)
    Second draft and final draft.
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Apr 18 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Apr 4 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Feb 28 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Feb 7 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Jan 10 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Jan 17 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Jan 24 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Jan 3 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Mar 21 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Mar 28 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Mar 7 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 May 16 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 May 23 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 May 9 (Box 3)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Dec 12 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Dec 19 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 May 30 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Nov 21 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1941 Nov 28 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Apr 9 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Jan 15 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Jan 2 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Jan 22 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Jan 29 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Mar 12 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Mar 19 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show for Camel Cigarettes script, 1942 Mar 26 (Box 4)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1938 Dec 12 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1938 Dec 19 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1938 Dec 26 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Apr 17 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Apr 24 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Feb 13 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Feb 20 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Feb 27 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Feb 6 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jan 16 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jan 2 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jan 9 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jul 17 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jul 3 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jun 12 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jun 19 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jun 26 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Jun 5 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Mar 20 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 Mar 6 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 May 29 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1939 May 8 (Box 1)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Apr 6 (Box 5)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Feb 3 (Box 5)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Jan 20 (Box 5)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Jan 27 (Box 5)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Jan 6 (Box 5)
    With First Spot script pages that may or may not be related to this episode.
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Apr 28 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 Jun 2 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 May 12 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1945 May 5 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1946 Jan 17 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1946 Jan 18 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1946 Jan 2 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1946 Jan 21 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1946 Jan 22 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, 1946 Jan 3 (Box 6)
  - Al Pearce Show script, Feb 3 no year (Box 8)
    Dated Feb 3, no year.
  - Al Pearce Show script, no date (Box 8)
  - Backstage in Broadcasting, 1941 Feb 17 (Box 3)
  - Backstage in Broadcasting, 1941 Feb 26 (Box 3)
  - Backstage in Broadcasting, 1941 Mar 3 (Box 3)
  - Elmer and Arlene - New Year's 1946 Special Broadcast script, 1946 Jan 1 (Box 6)
  - First spot script pages, no date (Box 8)
    May be related to Al Pearce show, Jan. 6, 1945 or Jan. 20, 1945.
  - First Vignette script, 1943 Mar 24 (Box 4)
    Appears to be for Elmer Blurt.
  - Fun Valley script, 1942 Jul 11 (Box 4)
    La Jolla benefit dance and party winner.
  - Fun Valley script, 1943 Dec 12 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1943 Dec 19 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1943 Dec 26 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1943 Dec 5 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1943 Nov 28 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1943 Nov 7 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Feb 13 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Feb 20 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Feb 27 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Feb 6 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jan 16 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jan 2 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jan 23 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Mar 12 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Mar 19 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Mar 5 (Box 4)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Apr 16 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Apr 2 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Apr 23 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Apr 30 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Apr 9 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jul 16 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jul 2 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jul 23 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jul 30 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jul 9 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jun 11 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jun 18 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jun 25 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 Jun 4 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 May 14 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 May 21 (Box 5)
  - Fun Valley script, 1944 May 7 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1944 Dec 9 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1944 Jul 20 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1944 Oct 10 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Apr 7 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Jan 27 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Mar 3 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Mar 31 (Box 5)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Apr 21 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Jun 16 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Jun 2 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Jun 23 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Jun 30 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 Jun 9 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 May 19 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer script, 1945 May 26 (Box 6)
  - Here Comes Elmer scripts, no date (Box 5)
    Identified as Episode No.1 (2 copies); Episode No.6; and Live Openings and Closings (3 copies).
  - KNX-TRA Promo script, 1941 Feb 28 (Box 3)
  - Lady Barber spot script pages, no date (Box 8)
    May be related to Al Pearce show, Jan. 20, 1945.
  - Life of Elmer Blurt script, no date (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous script pages, no dates (Box 8)
    May be vignettes, sketches, or revised script pages.
  - Pearce Show script, 1945 May 26 (Box 6)
- Transcription discs
  - Al Pearce, Jan 30 no year (Box 12)
    16" sound disc, part 2.
  - Al Pearce, Jan 18 no year (Box 13)
    16" sound disc, part 1 of 3.
  - Al Pearce, Jan 23 no year (Box 13)
    16" sound disc.
  - Al Pearce, Jan 25 no year (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce, no date (Box 13)
    16" sound disc. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce - Dole Pineapple, 1939 Dec 6 (Box 14)
    16" sound disc, part 1. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce - Dole Pineapple, 1939 Dec 6 (Box 14)
    16" sound disc, part 2. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce - Dole Pineapple, 1940 Mar 13 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce audition, no date (Box 9)
    12" sound disc, sides 3 and 4.
  - Al Pearce audition, no date (Box 10)
    12" sound disc, sides 1 and 2.
  - Al Pearce audition, 1943 Jun 28 (Box 15)
    16" sound disc, parts 1 and 3. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 10 (Box 9)
    12" sound disc, parts 1 and 3.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 10 (Box 9)
    12" sound disc, parts 2 and 4.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 12 (Box 9)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 12 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 4 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 4 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 5 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 6 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 6 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1945 Dec 7 (Box 10)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1946 Jan 2 (Box 10)
    12" sound disc, parts 1 and ?.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 16 (Box 11)
    16" sound disc, Western, parts 1 and 3.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 16 (Box 11)
    16" sound disc, Western, part 2.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 16 (Box 11)
    16" sound disc, Eastern, part 2.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 16 (Box 11)
    16" sound disc, Eastern, parts 1 and 3.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 30 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 30 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 30 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 30 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Sep 6 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Sep 6 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Sep 6 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Sep 6 (Box 11)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 23 (Box 12)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 23 (Box 12)
    16" sound disc, parts 1 and 3.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 12 (Box 12)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 12 (Box 12)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 19 (Box 12)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 26 (Box 12)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 5 (Box 12)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Oct 11 (Box 12)
    16" sound disc, parts 1 and 3
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 2 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 2 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 9 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Aug 9 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Nov 1 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Oct 11 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Oct 18 (Box 13)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 5 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jun 28 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Nov 8 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Nov 8 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Oct 4 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1941 Feb 14 (Box 14)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1944 Apr 23 (Box 14)
    16" sound disc, part 1 of 2. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce Show, May 15 no year (Box 14)
    16" sound disc, side 2. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Jul 19 (Box 15)
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Sep 13 (Box 15)
    16" sound disc, Eastern, part 2. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Al Pearce Show, 1940 Sep 13 (Box 15)
    16" sound disc, Western, parts 1 and 3. RESTRICTED ACCESS - Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.